All set with the firewood.
嘿咻 柴薪准备完毕
Bought it at the management office.
在管理处买的
BURN RESIDUE DISPOSAL AREA
(丢弃区)
Found the burn residue disposal area too.
也找到柴火灰烬的丢弃区了
Now to set up the campfire
在她们两个来之前
before they get here.
赶紧搭篝火…
LAID-BACK CAMP SEASON 3
《摇曳露营△ (第三季)》
EPISODE 5: BONFIRE AND BEEF FEAST
(第5话 篝火和牛肉盛宴)
Rin's campfire set!
小凛的焚火组
YESTERDAY
(昨天)
I might be a bit late to the campsite,
我应该会比较晚到露营场
so I'll leave this with you.
这个就先放你那里吧
Thank you, Rin!
谢谢你 小凛
First, put the firewood on the fire pit.
先把柴薪放到焚火台上
The world heritage site, Nirayama Reverberatory Furnaces.
世界遗产 韭山反射炉
Nope.
不行
Guess I'll have to chop the firewood properly.
果然还是得乖乖劈柴呢
And then…
然后…
Be careful with the blade
因为柴刀很锋利
because it's very sharp.
用的时候一定要注意安全
I used to brute chop the wood by force,
虽然我以前也是靠蛮力在劈柴
but it's dangerous and can break the blade.
但这样很危险 也有可能弄坏柴刀
Now I use the batoning method.
后来就改用背敲法劈柴了
Batoning?
背敲法?
Batoning is a method used
所谓的"背敲法"
when chopping wood
是一种用小刀或柴刀等
with a small knife or hatchet, tools lighter and smaller than an axe.
比斧头更小更轻的刀具劈柴时 会使用的手法
Strike the back of the blade with a wooden stick to slowly split the wood.
可以用木棒敲击刀具的刀背 慢慢将柴劈开
Good.
很好
Some of these are really tough to crack.
有些硬得不得了 真的很难劈开呢
Task complete.
劈好柴了
It's hot!
好烫
While waiting for the fire to grow,
等火生起来的时间里
"AMAZAKE (SWEET RICE WINE)" it's time for outdoor cooking experiment!
(甜酒) 户外料理实验 Part 2
"EASY AMAZAKE COOKIE" For today's experiment,
(简单的甜酒饼干) 今天的料理实验
we will be making simple and easy amazake cookies using a frying pan.
要用平底锅做简单的甜酒饼干
"INGREDIENTS"
(食材 无盐奶油40g 蛋黄1颗) 首先 将奶油放入平底锅加热融化
Let it cool
等稍微冷却后
and the egg yolk, then mix well.
再加入蛋黄 并搅拌均匀
This recipe doesn't call for the egg white,
因为这次不会用到蛋白
so let's fry it up and eat it with some salt.
就煎熟撒盐吃掉吧
"INGREDIENTS: 5TBSP POWDERED AMAZAKE" Next,
(食材 粉末甜酒5大匙) 接着 将粉末甜酒
and mix well.
倒进保鲜袋混合均匀
Then, add the ingredients from the pan into the bag and knead.
再将刚才调制好的蛋黄 加进去慢慢揉捏
Then, scoop out a spoonfuls of the dough
然后用汤匙舀出一口大小的面团
and flatten it into cookie shapes in the frying pan.
在平底锅里平铺成饼状
Cook it over low heat to avoid burning.
并用小火煎烤 以免烤焦
Once one side is cooked, flip it over to cook the other side.
煎好一面后 再翻过来煎另一面
Finally, set it aside to cool and for the fat to solidify.
最后放在一旁冷却 等待油脂凝固
And it's done!
饼干就完成啦
Not only is it easy to make,
不仅简单
but it's also great to make at a group camp.
感觉也能在团体露营时 和大家一起做
This
这个
tastes like the crust of a melon bread.
吃起来有点像菠萝面包的酥皮呢
Though it takes some effort,
虽然有些费工
who would've thought you could make melon bread using just a frying pan?
不过平底锅 原来也能做菠萝面包啊
If I can make it during a group camp…
如果在团体露营时做出来…
"You're amazing, Nadeshiko!"
抚子好厉害
Everyone will probably praise me.
大家应该会这么说吧
It's so peaceful here.
这里真宁静呢
Must be fun to play in the river here during summer.
如果夏天来 在河川里玩玩水应该也很有趣
Those ladies mentioned the train needed to be linked before it goes up a slope.
大姐姐们说的 电车要先合体才能爬上去的坡道
That must be the slope.
应该就是那个吧
It's really something, driving through such terrain.
真的行驶在一个很不得了的地方呢
Brr, it's chilly.
好冷
I feel like getting one of those camping chairs everyone has.
我也有点想买一把 大家那种露营椅了
Aya…
小绫
Come on, Nadeshiko, don't cry.
真是的 抚子 别哭了啦
We can still keep in touch whenever we want.
我们以后还是随时都能联络啊
Aya,
小绫
I promise I'll come back to visit during winter break!
我寒假时 一定会回来玩的
Got it.
知道了
And I'll definitely swing by your place too.
我也一定会去抚子那边玩的
Take care of yourself.
要保重哦
Aya…
小绫
Rin and Aya hanging out together,
小凛和小绫居然会一起去玩
hard to believe they'd get along so well.
感觉真不可思议呢
It takes about two hours to get from Hatanagi to here.
从畑薙到这里要两小时
They should be almost here.
她们应该差不多快到了吧
Hatanagi Dam.
畑薙水坝
Dam?
水坝?
A dish with a playful touch is superb!
这种充满玩心的料理真棒呢
Fun to play and delicious to eat!
既有趣又好吃
I must learn well.
我也得好好学习
Yes! A playful touch…
对了 充满玩心…
Let's make this!
就决定做这个了
Hey, Nadeshiko!
喂 抚子
You guys finally made it!
你们终于来啦
It's been three months…
三个月没…
Aya!
小绫
Battered and bruised.
遍体鳞伤
I leave the rest to you…
剩下的 就交给你了
Leave what to me?
什么东西?
Pitching the tent and stuff…
比如搭帐篷…之类的
I guess it can't be helped.
真拿你没办法呢
You don't look nearly as tired, Rin.
不过小凛看上去没那么累耶
I'm used to it.
毕竟我已经习惯了啊
Ayano's camping equipment.
绫乃的露营装备
MOUNTAIN CLIMBING TENT, DOWN FEATHER SLEEPING BAG, AIR MAT, HEADLIGHT
(羽绒睡袋 登山用帐篷) (充气床垫 头灯)
That's some nice gear you've got there.
你的装备还挺不错的呢
Must be expensive.
应该很贵吧
They're all used stuff.
这些全都是二手的
Didn't cost me an arm and a leg.
所以没花多少钱哦
Checking out others' camping gear
每次看到别人的露营装备
always gets me excited.
都会莫名有些兴奋呢
Compact stuff is seriously expensive.
体积小的装备真的很贵耶
But you can't carry much on a bike,
偏偏机车又载不了多少东西
so you've got to pay the hefty price for the petites.
如果不买小一点 就装不下去了
I get that.
我懂
This is a tiny tent.
这个帐篷也超小的呢
Isn't that a single-wall tent?
那是单层帐吧?
Single-wall?
单层帐?
A single-wall tent is essentially
所谓的单层帐
a lightweight tent that's waterproof and breathable on its own,
就是帐篷本身具备防水和透湿力
without an outer fly.
没有外帐的轻量帐篷
It's mainly used for mountaineering.
主要作为登山帐篷使用
Since it's made from a single piece of fabric,
因为整体只用到一块布料
setting it up and taking it down is super easy.
不论搭帐或收账都非常轻松
This tent is so easy to set up.
这个帐篷搭起来好简单哦
Even a camping novice like me can do it.
就算是我这个露营新手 也能轻松搭起来哦
Then do it yourself.
那你就自己搭啊
All set up.
搭设完毕
"DIDN'T DO ANYTHING" Ta-da, done!
(结果什么都没做的人) 完成了
It's about time
那么差不多
SUPER TASTY 100% BEEF HAMBURG STEAK
(超好吃100%汉堡排)
to start preparing dinner.
该来准备晚餐了吧
Hamburg steak!
是汉堡排
Is this the fabled hamburg steak?
这就是那个汉堡排吗
Yes, yes!
没错…
It's 100% beef! It's super delicious!
它是用纯牛肉做的 真的很好吃哦
Now to fry 'em up…
那么 赶紧来煎…
Aya, wait!
小绫 等一下
The hamburg steak.
这个汉堡排
It needs to be heated in water along with the bag at a low temperature first.
要先连同袋子一起 泡在水里低温加热哦
At a low temperature?
低温?
Let's get cooking.
马上开始做料理
RAW HAMBURG STEAK
(生汉堡排)
Raw hamburg steak must be vacuum-sealed
生的汉堡排 必须在真空包装的状态下
or placed in a zip lock bag with the air squeezed out.
或将汉堡排装进附夹链的保鲜袋里 并且尽量挤出空气
Then, use a thermometer to monitor and adjust the heat to keep the water
再用温度计一边确认温度 一边调整火力
at a temperature just below boiling
让水保持在不会沸腾的温度
for heating it indirectly.
进行隔水加热
If the temperature gets too high, the meat will become tough.
一旦温度过高 肉就会变硬
But if it's too low, it won't be sterilised.
但温度过低 又会无法杀菌
Keeping it at the right temperature is tricky.
实在很难精准掌控温度呢
So that's what you have to do.
原来是这样啊
It's a sleeping bag bug.
是睡袋虫
All right. I'll get started on the beef stew too.
那么 我也来开始煮炖牛肉吧
Yay! Beef stew!
炖牛肉
What's this?
这是什么?
Oh, this…
这是…
Pot…
锅子…
What are you looking for, Rin?
凛 你在找什么呀?
Mum.
妈妈
I was thinking of making beef stew for this upcoming camping trip.
这次去露营 我想煮炖牛肉
Have we got a spare pot?
家里有多的锅子吗
One big enough for three.
要能煮三人份的
Oh, my. You sure are putting some thought into your cooking now.
哎呀 你也开始会做些精致料理了啊
I don't think beef stew counts.
炖牛肉不算精致料理吧
You just throw the roux in and cook it.
只要把料理块丢进去煮一煮就好了
Let's see…
我想想哦
A spare pot, huh?
多的锅子吗
The one you've been using is pretty small.
你之前用的锅子确实太小了呢
Oh, that's right.
对了…
How about this?
这个怎么样?
It's a pot I used back when I lived alone.
这是我之前独居的时候用的锅子
That's an oddly-shaped pot.
它的形状长得好奇怪哦
This is a pressure pot.
这是压力锅哦
Unlike ordinary pressure cookers, this one is made of aluminium.
跟普通的压力锅不一样 这个是铝制的
It's lightweight and practical.
所以不仅轻巧 还很好用
It is light.
确实很轻呢
And all you need is
而且就算是用小火
cook it over low heat to get that pressure in and make delicious meals.
只要加压 就能把食物炖得很入味
It's perfect for camping, isn't it?
不觉得很适合露营用吗
I see.
原来如此
Make beef stew with a pressure pot, huh?
用压力锅煮炖牛肉吗
By the way, how do you open this thing?
话说 这要怎么开啊?
So that's a pressure pot.
原来那是压力锅啊
Beef stew.
炖牛肉
Firstly, in the pressure pot,
首先 在压力锅里
add the bite-sized beef shank and sauté in olive oil.
倒入切成一口大小的牛腱肉 并用橄榄油拌炒
Then, add water and red wine.
接着再倒入水和红酒
Let it simmer while skimming off any foam that forms.
一边炖煮 一边捞起浮沫
Next, cover the pot, pressurise it,
接着盖上盖子加压
and simmer over low heat for about 30 minutes.
再以小火炖煮30分钟左右
Once the beef shank is cooked,
等牛腱肉煮好后
replace half of the broth with water.
将一半的汤汁替换成水
Then, add onions, potatoes, and carrots.
再加入洋葱 土豆 胡萝卜
This time, pressure cook for only about five minutes.
这次只要加压5分钟左右就好
"BEEF STEW" Finally,
(炖牛肉) 最后
"SLICED MUSHROOMS" add roux and pre-boiled mushrooms,
(切片蘑菇) 加入料理块和事先用水煮过的蘑菇
and simmer until the sauce thickens.
煮到汤汁变浓稠
And there you have it.
就完成了
The tendon in the beef shank
牛腱肉只要慢慢炖煮
becomes incredibly tender when slow-cooked.
里面的胶质就会变得非常软嫩呢
Melt-in-your-mouth beef is the best.
软软嫩嫩的牛腱肉确实很好吃呢
But actually,
不过
I've already prepared the beef shank at home.
其实我已经在家里 提前处理好牛腱肉了
My mum said it would release a lot of fat.
因为我妈说会炖出很多牛油
It's better not to cook it on-site.
还是不要在现场煮比较好
Keeping all the broth would make it too greasy, right?
如果把汤汁全都保留下来 肯定会变得很腻吧
The calorie count would have gone through the roof.
卡路里大概会爆表吧
TIMER
(计时器)
The hamburg steaks should be ready.
这边应该也可以捞起来了吧
That's a lot of meat juice!
流了好多汤汁出来哦
"SUPER TASTY 100% BEEF HAMBURG STEAK" Yep.
(超好吃100%汉堡排) 没错…
If you had cooked this straight away, you'd have gotten a sea of meat juice.
如果用普通的方式煎这个汉堡排 可是会变成肉汁海哦
That's why
所以
you have to warm it up over low heat first.
一开始要先用低温隔水加热
Then, make an opening
再把袋子的一端稍微剪开
and pour the meat juices into a container.
像这样把肉汁倒到其他容器里才行
I see.
原来如此
If we had skipped that step, the clean-up would be a huge pain.
如果直接用平底锅煎 应该会变得很可怕吧
Fat freezes quickly in winter.
毕竟冬天油脂很容易凝固
Without hot water, it'll be a real hassle cleaning the pan.
没有热水的话 清洗起来也很不方便
When I bought a grill last year,
去年 我刚买焚火台的时候
we had a barbecue camp.
我们曾挑战过一次烤肉露营
-We got carried away -Meat is so good!
-肉好好吃 -当时不小心太得意忘形
-and made so much grilled pork belly -The best!
-好好吃 -烤了很多猪肉串和五花肉
The grill was drenched in grease, fat, and oil.
结果焚火台被喷得都是油
It was a nightmare.
变得超可怕的
How young and naive we were back then.
那时候的我们还很年轻呢
Well, we grow and learn through mistakes.
人总是要经历过失败 才会慢慢长大呢
Making the clean-up process as easy as possible
尽可能让整理过程轻松一些
is also crucial when preparing camping meals, Aya.
也是制作露营料理时 很重要的一点哦 小绫
That's some valuable advice.
真是宝贵的经验之谈呢
I'll keep it in mind.
我会牢记在心的
All that's left to do is
最后
to fry the hamburg steaks until the sides are charred…
只要把汉堡排的表面煎到略焦…
Hey, Nadeshiko.
欸 抚子
We've taken cared of the excess grease.
反正已经把多余的油脂分离出来了
Why don't we try grilling the steaks over the open fire?
如果只剩下烤的步骤 要不要直接用火烤烤看?
We can stick them on chopsticks and rotate them while we grill.
像这样插在筷子上 边转边烤
Great idea!
好主意…
Now we're camp cooking.
超有露营的感觉啊
Looks like the meat you see in manga.
感觉很像在烤漫画里 经常出现的那种肉呢
Replace the chopsticks with bones and you have the exact same thing.
如果把筷子换成骨头 就真的是漫画肉了
That aroma of the meat juices searing over direct heat
这股用直火炙烧的肉汁香气
is so tempting…
真让人受不了啊
I can hardly resist taking a bite.
好想直接咬下去哦
I feel you.
我懂
But we must resist the temptation.
但是要好好忍住
Eating undercooked hamburg steak can be dangerous.
如果汉堡排没有完全煮熟会很危险
Remember to cut it open and check the inside.
记得要切开确认一下里面的状况
RICE
(白饭)
Beef stew, check.
炖牛肉煮好了
Hamburg steaks, check.
汉堡排也煮好了
Rice, check.
饭也煮好了
Omelettes, check.
欧姆蛋也准备好咯
Leave the plating to me!
摆盘部分就交给我吧
I've got an idea in mind!
我有个好主意
Rice on both sides…
白饭放在两边
Place the hamburg steak here…
汉堡排放在这里
Then, pour the onion sauce and beef stew…
再倒入洋葱酱和炖牛肉
Hatanagi Dam Beef Stew Hamburg Steak Omurice
畑薙水坝炖牛肉欧姆汉堡排饭
complete!
完成了
It's the Hatanagi Dam!
是畑薙水坝
That's a long name.
名字好长
I was inspired by the dam curry I had in Senzu.
其实这个灵感来自 我之前在千头吃的水坝咖喱饭
This dish represents the Hatanagi Dam you guys visited.
这可是照着你们去过的 畑薙水坝做出来的哦
That was a hellishly long and dangerous road, huh, Rin?
那真是一条又远又危险的道路呢 小凛
I never want to go there by bike again.
已经不想再骑机车过去了
You girls went through a lot.
辛…辛苦你们了
Yo!
嗨
Is this Takanotsume? (Japanese hawk-claw chilli)
这是鹰爪椒吗
It represents the suspension bridge you crossed.
这个代表你们走过的吊桥哦
Takanotsume with beef stew, not a combination you see every day.
用鹰爪椒配炖牛肉 真是少见的组合啊
We eat it this way a lot in our house.
我家的炖牛肉倒是经常放呢
You can pick it out if you're not good with spicy.
如果不敢吃辣 可以放到旁边
But if you can handle the heat while biting into it,
不过如果能边咬边吃
you'll experience a whole new flavour with the spicy beef stew.
肯定能品尝到别有一番风味的 辣味炖牛肉哦
All right. Let's dig in while it's hot!
好了…赶紧趁热吃吧
I'm digging in.
我要开动了
So this is Hamamatsu's legendary 100% beef hamburg steak.
这就是滨松超有名的纯牛肉汉堡排
Bring it on!
来吧
Meat…!
肉…
The texture of this meat is not only firm
这肉的口感不仅扎实
but also gets more flavourful as you chew.
而且还越嚼越香
The texture is perfection!
未免太有嚼劲了吧
"BEEF STEW" While it's delicious paired with beef stew,
(炖牛肉) 虽然搭配炖牛肉一起吃也很赞
"ONION SAUCE" it's absolutely heavenly when eaten
(洋葱酱) 但搭配洋葱酱吃
with onion sauce!
简直是人间美味啊
Aya, where did you buy this hamburg steak from?
小绫 这个汉堡排是在哪里买的?
R… Rin, calm down…
小…小凛 你冷静一点
I'll tell you in a moment.
我等等会告诉你的
The beef shank in Rin's beef stew is so tender and tasty.
小凛的炖牛肉里的牛腱肉 炖得又软又嫩的好好吃哦
The rich broth goes perfectly with rice.
有些浓郁的汤汁 也很适合用来配白饭呢
Though it's simple,
虽然很简单
the soft, fluffy, and runny omelette acts as a perfect complement.
但滑滑嫩嫩的半熟欧姆蛋 也完美地达到调和的作用
What a feast!
真是大饱口福啊
Now…
接下来
It's this guy's turn.
换这家伙了呢
So spicy!
好辣
Yet so good!
但是 好好吃
Right?
对吧
I see.
原来如此
It's like how you feel terrified when crossing the bridge,
这种感觉就好像过桥时 会觉得很可怕
but when you look back on it, it's a fond memory.
但事后回想起来 又会觉得很有趣
So that's what you aimed to depict with the Takanotsume, huh?
原来你是想用鹰爪椒 表现出畑薙大吊桥的这一面啊
You're a genius, Nadeshiko!
抚子 你太厉害了
Well, I didn't really think that deeply.
我其实没有想那么多啦
Your plates are almost out of onion sauce.
你们盘子里的洋葱酱 差不多快吃完了呢
This is the time
这时候
to open the dam blocking the river…
就要把挡住河川的水坝移开
Open the gate!
放水
So this is the little joy you get with dam curry.
原来水坝咖喱饭还有这种小乐趣啊
We're having beef stew, though.
虽然今天加的是炖牛肉
Fun, right?
挺有趣的吧
But
不过
that's not all you can do with the dam beef stew!
水坝炖牛肉的花招可不只这些哦
Meat juice oil lamp!
肉汁油灯
I got the idea for this from the canned tuna oil lamp.
这是我从金枪鱼罐头油灯得到的灵感
Just stick a piece of thick cotton thread in the meat juice
只要在肉汁里插上一根粗棉线
and cool it down in the river.
再放到河里冷却一下就可以了
Nice! It works!
太好了 好像可以用呢
It cuts the grease and saves the environment.
而且还能减少油污 感觉挺环保的呢
I swear I can smell barbecue.
总觉得好像有股烧肉味
This is practically a barbecue-scented candle!
这根本是烧肉香氛吧
Pork skewers and curry.
又是猪肉串 又是咖喱的
You sure had a feast on your way here.
你根本都在吃嘛
After that,
后来
I took the ABT-racked train here.
我搭了ABT式列车到这里
It was small and retro, so cute!
那台车又小又复古 长得很可爱哦
Is that so?
这样啊…
We went to many suspension bridges
我们也走了很多吊桥
and a lot of places and had a blast.
去了各种各样的地方 玩得很开心哦
We even went to the tip of Shizuoka.
还一路走到静冈的角角呢
The tip?
角角?
Look.
你看 就是这里
Doesn't that look like a tip?
不觉得长得很像角吗
You guys sure went far.
你们跑到这么远啊
We got carried away,
结果不小心跑太远
and now my bottom and shoulders are sore.
害屁股和肩膀都超痛的
Good work making it this far.
辛苦你了
If I count today's total,
这样算下来
I drove about 180 kilometres.
我们也骑了180公里左右
Might as well have gone all the way to Yamanashi.
还不如直接骑去山梨呢
Then before you leave, you could swing by my place.
那你可以回去前 绕过来我家一趟哦
That's something I can't promise.
这我真的办不到
But someday, I'll ride my bike to your place
不过 总有一天我会骑机车
and we'll hang out.
去你家找你玩的
I'll save up
我要把打工钱存下来
to buy a bigger bike
买一台更大台的机车
and ride it
骑着它
to lots of places…
到各种各样的地方
Aya?
小绫?
I had a lot of fun today, Aya.
今天真的很开心呢 小绫
Good night.
晚安
Ow…
好痛…
You're up early, Nadeshiko.
抚子 你已经起床了啊
Good morning, Aya.
小绫 早安
Mornings in the mountains sure are cold.
山谷里的早晨 真的很冷呢
Right?
对吧
I have amazake. Want some?
我这里有甜酒 你要喝吗
Sure.
好啊…
Here.
给你
Thanks.
谢谢
I just love
我啊
sipping on something warm
在露营的早晨 最喜欢像这样
while watching the morning sun come out
一边喝着热乎乎的东西
and everything light up when I'm camping.
一边看周遭的景色慢慢变亮了
Yeah…
我好像…
I can relate.
能懂那种感觉呢
NEXT EPISODE: SEE YOU AGAIN
(下集 那么 改天再见)
WHEN ENJOYING CAMPING, BE SURE TO FOLLOW THE RULES
(享受露营时…) (务必遵守露营场和其设施的规定)
DON'T FORGET TO PUT OUT YOUR CAMPFIRE AND DISPOSE OF YOUR GARBAGE.
(别忘了灭火和带走垃圾)
TEMPERATURES CAN CHANGE QUICKLY, SO CHECK THE WEATHER FORECAST BEFOREHAND.
(由于气温可能会急速变化) (记得事先确认天气预报)
WEAR WARM CLOTHING IF NECESSARY TO PREVENT COLD.
(必要时穿着保暖衣物防寒)